<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Alfredo&#39;s Sandbox</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Alfredo&#39;s Sandbox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R&#39;s Demise Higly Overblown</title>
      <link>/2019/11/11/r-s-demise-higly-overblown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/11/r-s-demise-higly-overblown/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will provide evidence that contradicts recent reports that the R Programming languange is declining in popularity.
In last few months I have come across several blog posts that suggest that Python is reducing the demand for R. Yet, it contradicts what I am seeing in my day to day life. Many analyst at work from different parts of the business that are not associated with data science or software engineering are adopting the R programming language because it feels more comfortable than Python and they are not interested in building software or building production pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEZ UP YOUR RODBC HIVE QUERIES</title>
      <link>/2019/03/24/tez-up-your-rodbc-hive-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/24/tez-up-your-rodbc-hive-queries/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will show you how you can add TEZ options to your Hive ODBC connection and thus your RODBC queries in R.
Hive only a few years ago was rare occurrence in most corporate data warehouses, but these days Hive, Spark, Tez, among others open source data warehouses are all the buzz in the corporate world and data analysts need to adapt to this changing world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ode to R, Happy 25th Birthday</title>
      <link>/2018/03/31/ode-to-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/31/ode-to-r/</guid>
      <description>As R turns 25 years old this year, I thought it would only be appropriate to thank the creators of R, Ross Ihaka and Robert Gentleman, as well as the R global community for changing my life. I started learning R in 2014 because I was tired at how SAS had become like a curmudgeon old monopoly rather than a true innovator. But I guess that is what happens to companies with a first mover advantage; they get complacent and feel invincible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>